Guide to the J. Deryl Hart Records, 1957 - 1980 (bulk 1960-1963) UA.03.58.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1960-1980
  - Inter-university Committee on the Superior Student, 1962-1963 (Box 25, Folder 319)
  - Invitations, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 320)
  - J Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 321)
  - Jones, Dr. Thomas T., 1962 (Box 25, Folder 322)
  - Junior Science Symposium (Box 25, Folder 323)
  - K Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 324)
  - L Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 325)
  - Law and Contemporary Problems, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 326)
  - Library of Congress, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 327)
  - M Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 328)
  - Mc Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 329)
  - Manchester, Alan K., 1960 (Box 26, Folder 330)
  - Mary Duke Biddle Foundation (Box 26, Folder 331)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1960-1961 (Box 26, Folder 332)
  - Medical Education Questionnaires, 1960-1962 (Box 26, Folder 333)
  - Medicare, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 334)
  - Memoranda, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 335)
  - Memorial Church Fund, Inc., 1960 (Box 26, Folder 336)
  - Methodist Church
    - Brochures, Correspondence, and Reports (Box 26, Folder 337)
    - North Carolina Conference (Box 26, Folder 338)
    - Western North Carolina Conference (Box 26, Folder 339)
  - Michigan University, Center for the Study of Higher Education, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 340)
  - Murray, William D., 1962 (Box 26, Folder 341)
  - N Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 342)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 343)
  - National Association of College and University Food Services (Box 26, Folder 344)
  - National Association of Manufacturers, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 345)
  - National Commission on Accrediting, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 346)
  - National Industrial Conference Board, 1961-1963 (Box 26, Folder 347)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 348)
  - National Merit Scholarship Corporation (Box 26, Folder 349)
  - National Research Council, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 350)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 27)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 27, Folder 351)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 352)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (Box 27, Folder 353)
  - North Carolina
    - Advisory Committee to the United States Commission on Civil Rights (Box 27, Folder 354-355)
    - Board of Higher Education (Box 27, Folder 356)
    - Board of Science and Technology (Box 27, Folder 357)
    - College Conference, 1960-1962 (Box 27, Folder 358)
    - Cultural and Recreational Center, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 359)
    - Department of Public Instruction, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 360)
    - Educational Council on National Purposes, 1962-1963 (Box 27, Folder 361)
    - N.C. Governor
      - N.C. Governor's Commission on Education Beyond the High School
        - Publications and Reports
          - Community Colleges for North Carolina, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 362)
          - What? Who? How? When? (Box 27, Folder 363)
          - N.C. College Enrollment Trends, 1950-1980 (Box 28, Folder 364)
          - Projections in Full Enrollment in N.C. Colleges and Universities, 1962-1980 (Box 28, Folder 365)
          - Report to Governor's Commission on Education Beyond the High School, Jan. 19, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 366)
          - Report of the Governor's Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 2nd draft, Aug. 15, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 367)
          - The Report of the Governor's Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 368)
          - Fact Book on Higher Education in North Carolina, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 369)
          - General Reports (Box 29, Folder 370)
        - Correspondence and Reports (Box 29, Folder 371)
        - Recommendations on Education Beyond the High School (Box 29, Folder 372)
        - Committees of the N.C. Governor's Commission on Education Beyond the High School (Box 30)
          - Committee for the 375th Anniversary of the Birth of Virginia Dare, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 373)
          - Committee for the Central Coordinating Committee (Box 30, Folder 374)
          - Committee for the Cooperative Planning Between Public and Private Institutions and the Public Schools (Box 30, Folder 375)
          - Committee for the Community Colleges and New Colleges (Box 30, Folder 376)
          - Committee for the Development of System of Higher Education (Box 30, Folder 377)
          - Committee for Enrollment and Admissions Standards (Box 30, Folder 378)
          - Committee for Financing and Budgets (Box 30, Folder 379)
          - Committee for Long Range Growth Patterns (Box 30, Folder 380)
      - N.C. Governor's Office (Box 30, Folder 381)
      - N.C. Governor's Technical Advisory Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 30, Folder 382)
    - Press Association, 1961-1963 (Box 30, Folder 383)
    - N.C. Trade Fair, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 384)
  - O Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 385)
  - Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Studies (Box 30, Folder 386)
  - P Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 387)
  - Parkvue Hospital, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 388)
  - Plans, Inc., 1960 (Box 30, Folder 389)
  - Private Colleges (N.C.), 1963 (Box 30, Folder 390)
  - Questionnaires (Box 31, Folder 391)
  - Quinn, Galen W., 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 392)
  - R Correspondence (Box 31, Folder 393)
  - Research Triangle (Box 31, Folder 394-397)
  - Richardson Foundation (Box 31, Folder 398)
  - Rotary Club, 1960-1963 (Box 31, Folder 399)
  - S Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 400)
  - Sanford, Terry, 1961-1963 (Box 32, Folder 401)
  - Security Life and Trust Company, Winston-Salem, NC (Box 32, Folder 402)
  - Semans, Mary D.B.T., 1960-1963 (Box 32, Folder 403)
  - Seminar on American Strategy, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 404)
  - Shriners' Hospital (Proposed), 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 405)
  - South Atlantic Quarterly (Box 32, Folder 406)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (Box 32, Folder 407)
  - Southern University Conference (Box 32, Folder 408)
  - Spence, Hersey Everett, 1960-1963 (Box 32, Folder 409)
  - Spengler, Joseph John (Box 32, Folder 410)
  - Stanford University, School Planning Laboratory, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 411)
  - T Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 412)
  - Taft Institute of Government (Box 32, Folder 413)
  - Taxation, 1961-1963 (Box 32, Folder 414)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association (Box 32, Folder 415)
  - Television, 1960-1962 (Box 32, Folder 416)
  - Thomas, James Augustus (Memorial Service), 1962 (Box 32, Folder 417)
  - Tschaikovsky Foundation (Box 32, Folder 418)
  - Tuthill, Richard Lovejoy, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 419)
  - U Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 420)
  - United Health and Medical Research Foundation of South Carolina, Inc., 1962 (Box 32, Folder 421)
  - United States Government
    - Miscellaneous Letters (Box 32, Folder 422)
    - Health, Education, and Welfare Dept. and the Dept. of Education (Box 32, Folder 423)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Agency, 1961-1963 (Box 33, Folder 424)
    - National Defense Education Act (Box 33, Folder 425)
    - Peace Corps, 1961-1963 (Box 33, Folder 426)
    - State Department, 1960-1963 (Box 33, Folder 427)
    - Veterans' Administration (Box 33, Folder 428)
  - University Club (N.Y.), 1962 (Box 33, Folder 429)
  - V Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 430)
  - Vanderbilt University, 1960-1963 (Box 33, Folder 431)
  - W Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 432)
  - Wessel, Nils Y. (Box 33, Folder 433)
  - Womble, B.S., 1960-1963 (Box 33, Folder 434)
  - Y Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 435)
  - Z Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 436)
- Reports, 1960-1963
  Includes annual reports submitted by various university offices and departments to the President's Office. There is some consistency, from year to year, on the reports that were submitted but not all offices submitted reports each year.
  - 1960-1961
    - Alumni Affairs (Box 33, Folder 437)
    - Appointments Office (Box 33, Folder 438)
    - Bands (Box 33, Folder 439)
    - Bureau of Testing and Guidance (Box 33, Folder 440)
    - Choral Music (Box 33, Folder 441)
    - Dean of Arts and Sciences (Box 33, Folder 442)
    - Office of the Dean of Men (Box 33, Folder 443)
    - Bureau of Public Information (Box 33, Folder 444)
    - Divinity School (Box 34, Folder 445)
    - Duke Players (Box 34, Folder 446)
    - Duke University Press (Box 34, Folder 447)
    - Engineering, College of (Box 34, Folder 448)
    - Financial Aid Office (Box 34, Folder 449)
    - Forestry, School of (Box 34, Folder 450)
    - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences (Box 34, Folder 451)
    - Law and Contemporary Problems (Box 34, Folder 452)
    - Law, School of (Box 34, Folder 453)
    - Library (Box 34, Folder 454)
    - Medical Center (Box 34, Folder 455)
    - Nursing, School of (Box 34, Folder 456)
    - Physical Education and Athletics (Box 34, Folder 457)
    - Physical Education, Dept. of (Woman's College) (Box 34, Folder 458)
    - Public Relations, Vice President for (Box 34, Folder 459)
    - Campus Radio Station WDBS (Box 34, Folder 460)
    - Registrar (Box 34, Folder 461)
    - Religious Activities (Box 34, Folder 462)
    - Secretary, Office of the (Box 34, Folder 463)
    - Student Health Service (Box 34, Folder 464)
    - Division of Student Life (Box 34, Folder 465)
    - Summer Session (Box 34, Folder 466)
    - Trinity College, Office of the Dean (Box 34, Folder 467)
    - Woman's College (Box 34, Folder 468)
  - 1961-1962
    - Bands (Box 34, Folder 469)
    - Bureau of Testing and Guidance (Box 34, Folder 470)
    - Choral Music (Box 34, Folder 471)
    - Office of the Dean of Men (Box 34, Folder 472)
    - Debate Activities (Box 34, Folder 473)
    - Divinity School (Box 34, Folder 474)
    - Duke Players (Box 34, Folder 475)
    - Duke University Press (Box 34, Folder 476)
    - Engineering, College of (Box 34, Folder 477)
    - Forestry, School of (Box 34, Folder 478)
    - Institutional Advancement and the Woman's College (Box 34, Folder 479)
    - Law and Contemporary Problems (Box 34, Folder 480)
    - Law, School of (Box 34, Folder 481)
    - Library (Box 34, Folder 482)
    - Medical Center (Box 35, Folder 483)
    - Nursing, School of (Box 35, Folder 484)
    - Religious Activities (Box 35, Folder 485)
    - Research, Duke University Council on (Box 35, Folder 486)
    - Secretary, Office of the (Box 35, Folder 487)
    - Student Health (Box 35, Folder 488)
    - Division of Student Life (Box 35, Folder 489)
    - Student Union (Box 35, Folder 490)
    - Summer Session (Box 35, Folder 491)
    - Trinity College, Office of the Dean (Box 35, Folder 492)
    - Woman's College (Box 35, Folder 493)
  - 1962-1963
    - Bands (Box 35, Folder 494)
    - Building and Grounds (Box 35, Folder 495)
    - Bureau of Testing and Guidance (Box 35, Folder 496)
    - Office of the Dean of Men (Box 35, Folder 497)
    - Debate Activities (Box 35, Folder 498)
    - Duke Players (Box 35, Folder 499)
    - Engineering, College of (Box 35, Folder 500)
    - Forestry, School of (Box 35, Folder 501)
    - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences (Box 35, Folder 502)
    - Institutional Studies, Office of (Box 35, Folder 503)
    - Law, School of (Box 35, Folder 504)
    - Library (Box 35, Folder 505)
    - Nursing, School of (Box 35, Folder 506)
    - Summer Session (Box 36, Folder 507)
    - Trinity College, Office of the Dean (Box 36, Folder 508)
    - Woman's College (Box 36, Folder 509)
  - 1960-1963
    - Bands (Box 36, Folder 510)
    - Bureau of Testing and Guidance (Box 36, Folder 511)
    - Daedelus (Honors-Master's Program) (Box 36, Folder 512)
    - Dean of Arts and Sciences (Box 36, Folder 513)
    - Office of the Dean of Men (Box 36, Folder 514)
    - Divinity School (Box 36, Folder 515)
    - Division of Student Life (Box 36, Folder 516)
    - Duke Players (Box 36, Folder 517)
    - Duke University Press (Box 36, Folder 518)
    - Engineering, College of (Box 36, Folder 519)
    - Financial Aid Office (Box 36, Folder 520)
    - Forestry, School of (Box 36, Folder 521)
    - Law, School of (Box 36, Folder 522)
    - Library (Box 36, Folder 523)
    - Marine Laboratory (Box 36, Folder 524)
    - Medical School (Box 36, Folder 525)
    - Nursing, School of (Box 36, Folder 526)
    - Planning and Institutional Studies, Office of Vice President for (Box 36, Folder 527)
    - Provost (Box 36, Folder 528)
    - Public Relations, Vice President for (Box 36, Folder 529)
    - Registrar (Box 36, Folder 530)
    - Religious Activities (Box 36, Folder 531)
    - Research, Duke University Council on (Box 36, Folder 532)
    - Student Health (Box 36, Folder 533)
    - Student Union (Box 36, Folder 534)
    - Summer Session (Box 36, Folder 535)
    - Trinity College, Office of the Dean (Box 36, Folder 536)
    - Woman's College (Box 36, Folder 537)
- 1983 Additions (Accession 83-6)
  Includes copies of Hart's addresses and speeches, and additions to the subject files for Duke University. The subject files include materials about administrative reorganization, the budget, university business, and information for Board of Trustees' meetings.
  Access to Folders 565 and 579-581 is RESTRICTED. Please consult University Archives staff.
  - Addresses and Speeches, 1960-1968 (Box 37)
    - A. B. Duke Scholarship Finalists' Dinner, March 17, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 538)
    - Alumni Groups, 1960-1963 (Box 37, Folder 539)
    - Awards Convocation, May 1, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 540)
    - B. N. Duke Lectures, Introduction for E. Gombrich, March 22, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 541)
    - Civic Groups, 1960, 1962, and 1963 (Box 37, Folder 542)
    - Commencements, 1961-1963 (Box 37, Folder 543)
    - Dad's Day, Nov. 4, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 544)
    - Durham Civic Dinner for D. M. Knight, Sept. 19, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 545)
    - Duke-Durham Kickoff Dinner, Nov. 16, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 546)
    - Duke Press Dinner, Feb. 3, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 547)
    - Faculty, Addresses to, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 548)
    - Flag-Raising Ceremonies, 1960-1962 (Box 37, Folder 549)
    - Foreign Visitors (Box 37, Folder 550)
    - Founders' Day, 1960-1968 (Box 37, Folder 551)
      Includes programs and notes.
    - Freshmen Assemblies in the Chapel, 1960-1962 (Box 37, Folder 552)
    - James B. Duke Professorships' Dinner, May 17, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 553)
    - Commencement, Kannapolis, N.C. High School, June, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 554)
    - Kiwanis Club, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 555)
    - Law School, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 556)
      Includes lectures, welcoming remarks, and Law Day remarks.
    - Meet the Blue Devils, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 557)
    - Memorial Services, 1960 and 1962 (Box 37, Folder 558)
    - Rotary Club, Durham, N.C., Sept., 1962 (Box 37, Folder 559)
    - Symposia and Seminars, 1962-1963 (Box 37, Folder 560)
  - Subject Files, 1959-1964
    - Duke University
      - Administrative Reorganization
        - 1959-1961 (Box 37, Folder 561)
        - Personnel, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 562)
      - Budget
        - Educational, General, Estimates, and Proposals, 1961-1963 (Box 37, Folder 563)
        - Proposed, 1963-1964 (Box 37, Folder 564)
        - Salary Increases, Faculty and Administration, Aided by Duke Endowment Grants, 1961-1963 (Box 37, Folder 565)
          Access to Folder 565 is RESTRICTED: Personnel information.
      - Burch-Bremer Affair, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 566)
      - Clyde, Paul H., 1960 (Box 37, Folder 567)
      - Edens-Gross Controversy, 1959-1969 and 1964(?) (Box 37, Folder 568)
      - Development Reports: Physical Landscaping, Olmsted Brothers, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 569)
      - Financial, Miscellaneous: Salaries, Gifts, Grants, and Contracts, 1957-1964 (Box 37, Folder 570)
      - Georgia Surgical Society, undated (Box 37, Folder 571)
      - Graduate School: Report of the Subcommittee on Matters Related to the Graduate School, ca. 1960 (Box 37, Folder 572)
      - Hart, Deryl, "A Backward Glance," Report on Duke University, 1960-1963 (Box 37, Folder 573)
      - Long-Range Planning Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 574)
      - Medical Center Renovations, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 575)
      - Medicine, School of: Program Cost Study, 1961-1963 (Box 37, Folder 576)
      - Presidential Selection Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 577)
      - Student Handbooks, Statements for, undated and 1961 (Box 37, Folder 578)
      - Board of Trustees
        - Executive Committee Meetings, Aug. 11, 1960; Oct. 7, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 579)
          Access to Folder 579 is RESTRICTED: Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
        - Meeting, April 30-May 1, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 580)
          Access to Folder 580 is RESTRICTED: Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
        - President's Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1961-1963 (Box 37, Folder 581)
- 2000 Additions (Accession 2000-87)
  Includes additions to the subject files on Duke University.
  Access to Folder 584 is RESTRICTED. Please consult University Archives staff.
  - Duke University, [1960-1963]
    - Roads, Parking, and Traffic
      - [1960-1963] (Box 37, Folder 582)
      - [1962] (Box 37, Folder 583)
    - Knight, Douglas M., (Senior staff salaries), [1963] (Box 37, Folder 584)
      Access to Folder 584 is RESTRICTED: Personnel information.
    - Hart, Julian D.: Writings, Duke Encounters, [1974] (Box 37, Folder 585)
    - Gross, Paul, 1960 and 1974 (Box 37, Folder 586)
    - Duke Endowment and Duke University (Box 37, Folder 587)
    - Urban Renewal, Duke University Campus to the Expressway, 1963 (Box 37, Folder 588)